Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, there is a big workforce in
all of these factories. So, you might
wonder who exactly comprises this
workforce. Simply put, it's mostly
immigrants. Like, obviously, there are a
lot of prim and proper Americans in the
batch, but it was mostly immigrants. To
basically oversimplify this, not just
America, but the entire world is getting
privy to the knowledge of all the jobs
available in the United States. And a
lot of people wanted to come over and
start a new life. And also it helped
that life in these immigrants homelands
were not really that great, especially
if they were uniquely religious. The two
big waves of immigration you'll see are
people coming in from Europe to the east
coast and those coming in from Asia on
the west coast. This will lead to the
formation of two big hubs of immigrant
processing. Ellis Island right outside
of New York City and Angel Island right
outside of San Francisco. So let me
quickly explain something. If you're an
Uncle Sam American in this time period
with your own twisted racial beliefs on
the Ellis Island side, of course you're
going to want the lovely, hardworking,
mostly white Europeans in America
because they will create a better
society. But those Asians on the Angel
Island side, um, uh, so yeah, what I
mean is that in this time period, Ellis
Island was known as very welcoming. It
even had health checks and was seen as a
mostly great place. Angel Island, on the
other hand, was home to countless
interrogations, detentions, and long,
long stays, all instigated by deeply
rooted anti-Asian racism. And though
unrelated, here's a picture of me many,
many years ago on Angel Island. There's
no real historical significance here. I
honestly just wanted to show off that
I've been there. Anyway, the outcome of
all of this immigration is the formation
of lots of ethnic inclaves. This era is
the pure reason why there are things
like Chinatowns, Little Italies, Jewish
neighborhoods, and much more ethnic
areas around the US. We also see a lot
of internal migration in this time
period as well. For example, you have
lots of people from the rural
countryside moving into urban cities.
And finally, a bunch of
African-Americans are moving out of the
south cuz honestly, screw that goddamn
place. This would set the stage for
something later known as the Great
Migration. I think that's enough for
now, though. On the screen now, are AP
style questions for this topic. Pause
now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.